# Aric VanTroostenberghe

Detroit Metropolitan Area

aric.vant@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/aricvantroostenberghe

# **Summary**

Experienced Assembly Supervisor with a demonstrated history of working in the machine tool industry. Skilled in Computer Numerical Control (CNC), Lean Manufacturing, and Manufacturing Management. Strong operations professional with a Bachelor of Science (B.S.) focused in Management with a Concentration in the Manufacturing Sector from University of Phoenix.

# **Experience**



# Manufacturing Supervisor, Assembly

MAG IAS, LLC

Jan 2001 - Present (23 years 1 month)

Machine Builder Apprentice: January 2001 - 2004

- Apprentice Machine Builder for metal cutting machinery such as CNC, milling, transfer lines, etc.

Machine Builder: January 2004 - 2008

- Responsible for the construction, alignment, and qualification of CNC, milling, hone, transfer line, and similar metal cutting machinery. This includes the construction of work holding fixtures and spindles.

Machine Builder Leader: 2008 - April 2017

- Responsible for leading others in the construction, alignment, and qualification of CNC, milling, hone, and similar metal cutting machinery. This includes the development and implementation of related processes and procedures.

Manufacturing Supervisor - Assembly: April 2017 - Present

- Responsible for organizing, planning, and coordinating machine tool related assembly activities including management of personnel and processes.

### Quality Assurance Inspector

Design/Electro Linc

1999 - 2000 (1 year)

Responsible for testing and auditing the manufacturing quality of circuit board assemblies including both thru and surface mount devices

#### Mechanic/Laborer

Golf Country

1995 - 1999 (4 years)

General Laborer

Responsible for the maintenance and repair of equipment used to maintain the grounds

#### **Education**

# University of Phoenix

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Management with a Concentration in the Manufacturing Sector

2012 - 2014

## St. Clair County Community College

Classes for Machine Builder Certification 2001 - 2004

Required classes for Department of Labor certified Machine Builder apprentice program

#### **ITT Technical Institute-Troy**

Associate's of Applied Science, Electronics Engineering 1998 - 2000

M Marysville High School

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

**LEAN Champion Training** - Michigan Manufacturing Technology Center

Six Sigma Belt Training - Cummins Inc.

**Safety & Health General Industry - Level 1** - MIOSHA Training Institute, Macomb County Community College

**Supervisor Leadership Skills Training** - Michigan Manufacturing Technology Center

#### **Skills**

Manufacturing • Six Sigma • Quality Assurance • Machinery • Lean Manufacturing • Journeyman Toolmaker • Lean Manufacturing Training • Six Sigma Training • Cnc • Manufacturing Engineering